hey guys so we have a circle i want to
find the area of this red region of the
circle so let's call that x in order to
solve for x first i'm going to find this
blue sector right here and then i'm
going to subtract this orange triangle
right here and if we call the large
sector a and the triangle b we know that
a minus b is going to give us x first
let's solve for a if this is 60 degrees
right here we know this angle right here
is going to be 120 degrees the area of
an entire circle is pi r squared and
this is only 120 out of 360 degrees of
an entire circle so we'll say the
proportion 120 over 360. and 120 over
360 is the same thing as one third and
then the radius here is six so i'm going
to plug in 6 for r 6 squared is 36 and
then 1 3 of 36 is 12. so 12 pi is our
answer and we can even move it up here
to the a next let's look at this orange
triangle this is the same angle from
above so it's still 120 and now we don't
really need the 60 anymore and this side
of the triangle right here is a radius
as well so it's also going to be six
because they're both coming from the
center to the edge of the circle now we
don't even need the circle anymore
enhance and let's flip it around and
bisect this 120 degrees that's going to
give us 60 degrees for both sides of
this let's focus on this left triangle
and then we know it's a right angle
anytime you bisect that top angle in an
isosceles triangle it always meets at
right angles and this last angle is
going to be 30 degrees now we have a 30
60 90 triangle this is a special type of
triangle here's the notes right here on
andymath.com the side opposite the 30
degrees is always half the hypotenuse
this hypotenuse is 6 so this side right
here is going to be 3 and then the side
opposite the 60 is always square root of
3 times the smallest side so this right
here is gonna be three root three since
these two are similar triangles this is
also three root three and when we
combine them we get six root three let's
clean up the stuff we don't need now we
need to find the area of this triangle
it's gonna be one half base times height
the base is this six root three and the
height is three so six times one half is
three and then three root three times
three is nine root three so that's our
value for the triangle so let's change
these up here we'll make the a into the
twelve pi and we'll make the b into nine
root three and now we have the answer to
the question the area of this red region
is 12 pi minus 9 root 3.